Mating System: How individuals mate with each other. This is a discrete trait, and the options are Monogamous, Polygynous, Polyandrous, Polygamous, Promiscuous, and Unknown. Please code monogamous as 2, polygynous, polyandrous, and promiscuous as 4, and code polygamous as 6. Code unknown as N/A or empty. 
Group Size Outside of Reproduction: The size of the social group while not reproducing. This is a discrete trait, and the options are solitary (no sociality), small groups (2-10 individuals), medium groups (10-100 individuals), and large groups (100-1000 or more individuals). Please code solitary as 0, small groups as 2, medium groups as 4, and large groups as 6.
Age at Maturity: How old individuals in a species are on average when they become reproductively viable. This should be a number in years. 
Avg. life expectancy: How old individuals in a species are on average when they die. This should be a number in years. 
# offspring/reproductive bout: Number of offspring per reproductive event. This should be a number. If there is a range, take the average. 