Mating System: How individuals mate with each other. This is a discrete trait, and the options are Monogamous, Polygynous, Polyandrous, Polygamous, Promiscuous, and Unknown. Please code monogamous as 2, polygynous, polyandrous, and promiscuous as 4, and code polygamous as 6. Code unknown as N/A or empty. 
Social Dominance Hierarchy: How non-mating individuals in a group interact with one another. This is a discrete trait, and the options are No, Linear, Non-Linear, and Unknown. Please code no as 0, and linear or non-linear as 6. Code unknown as N/A or empty.  
Territoriality (males): Whether males of this species maintain territory, and how much territory. This is a discrete trait, and the options are No, Small territories, Large territories, and Unknown. Please code No as 0, small territories as 3, large territories as 6, and unknown as N/A or empty. 
Territoriality (females): Whether females of this species maintain territory, and how much territory. This is a discrete trait, and the options are No, Small territories, Large territories, and Unknown. Please code No as 0, small territories as 1, large territories as 2, and unknown as N/A or empty.
Group Size During Reproduction: The size of the social group while reproducing. This is a discrete trait, and the options are solitary (no sociality), small groups (2-10 individuals), medium groups (10-100 individuals), and large groups (100-1000 or more individuals). Please code solitary as 0, small groups as 2, medium groups as 4, and large groups as 6. 
Group Size Outside of Reproduction: The size of the social group while not reproducing. This is a discrete trait, and the options are solitary (no sociality), small groups (2-10 individuals), medium groups (10-100 individuals), and large groups (100-1000 or more individuals). Please code solitary as 0, small groups as 2, medium groups as 4, and large groups as 6.
Group Property: How social individuals act towards each other. This is a discrete trait, and the options are aggressive, interactional, and cooperative. Please code aggressive as 2, interactional as 4, and cooperative as 6. 
Age at Maturity: How old individuals in a species are on average when they become reproductively viable. This should be a number in years. 
Avg. life expectancy: How old individuals in a species are on average when they die. This should be a number in years. 
# offspring/reproductive bout: Number of offspring per reproductive event. This should be a number. If there is a range, take the average. 
# reproductive bouts/year: Number of offspring on average per year for a single individual. This should be a number. If there is a range, take the average. 
Migratory behavior: Whether or not an individual or group within the species migrates at some point during the year. This is a discrete trait, and the options are yes, no, “no, they migrate eventually”, and “no, the female will migrate for mate.” Please code no as 0, yes as 6, “no, they migrate eventually” as 2, and “no, the female will migrate for mate” as 4. 
Activity Pattern: How often an individual in the species will try to reproduce. This is a discrete trait, and the options are yearround, seasonal, opportunistic, and unknown. Please code yearround as 6, seasonal as 3, and opportunistic as 0. 
Habitat Complexity: Refers to the variety of structural features within an environment, such as the amount of cover, physical structure, and the arrangement of those features. This is a range from simple/open to complex, where simple/open is coded as 1 and complex is coded as 6. 
